https://umkc.edu/web-policy/privacy.asp

Introduction
UMKC is committed to protecting your privacy. We have established this Privacy Policy and are providing it to you so that you can understand the manner in which we collect and use your information and the efforts we use to protect it. Please note that this policy is for UMKC's web site only and does not apply to other 3rd party web sites linked to from our web site. Please check the privacy policies on those web sites for more information.
European Union's General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)
European Union's General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) affords individuals certain rights as to how their data is used and processed, and may give them rights to access, correct, or delete their data. UMKC and the University of Missouri System provides information on GDPR requirements and university processes at https://www.umsystem.edu/ums/is/infosec/gdpr
Personal Information Collected
UMKC recognizes the need for consumers to control the use and management of personal information. By personal information we mean information that can be used to identify or contact an individual. This may include, but is not limited to, a first and last name, a physical address, an email address, a student ID number or a phone number. If you are visiting our site to browse or find information about UMKC's services, you do not need to provide any personal information. If you decide to request information, however, we may collect this data so that we can provide information regarding your request.
Automatic Information Collected
Our website makes use of various technologies to collect information about types and versions of internet browsers used when accessing our web site. This information, and information about internet IP addresses, as well as date and time web pages are visited are stored in various security and traffic logs. We review these logs, using statistical analysis, in an effort to track and predict traffic patterns and estimate resource needs. Unless we are tracking down a technical problem or we suspect either fradulent behavior or illegal conduct, we do not trace specific user sessions.
Personal Information Use
UMKC uses personal information provided by you so that we can service you. Also note that we may need to transfer that information to our agents or employees of our service providers. We will not sell or trade your information to unrelated third parties.
Third Parties
We may partner with third parties to provide various products and services. When you sign up for these services or products, we will share required personal information that is necessary for the third party to provide the product or service to you. We take reasonable steps to ensure that these third parties are obligated to protect your information on our behalf. It is also against our policy to sell or trade information collected online without consumer consent. We may, however, release personal information if we are legally required to do so. If we are legally compelled to release information to a third party, you may not be notified of this release. Notification will be at the discretion of UMKC and will be based on the nature and conditions surrounding the release of information.
Supplemental Technologies
Our website uses cookies, session identifiers, JavaScript™ and browser detection technology to provide consumers with a more pleasant online experience. Many browsers provide consumers with the ability to disable some or all of these technologies. Disabling them, especially in the case of JavaScript™, may prevent you from viewing some web pages. Note that the cookies we use do not place any personally identifiable information on your computer.
Confidentiality and Security
UMKC takes reasonable steps to ensure that your information is protected. On our website, we use industry standard Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) encryption when collecting your personal information. Our website is hosted in a data center which makes use of multiple levels of redundant firewalls and database encryption to protect information. Internally, we limit access to your information to those employees or agents who we believe have reasonable need to use the information to provide products or services to you or to perform their jobs.
Updates to This Privacy Policy
This site has the right to make changes or additions to this policy at any time. Changes that do not affect use of personally identifiable information will be posted to the site. If you have questions regarding this policy, please check this policy periodically or contact the UMKC Webmaster.
Contact
Please direct all privacy related questions and concerns to webmaster@umkc.edu.
Questions?
Send us an email at
webmaster@umkc.edu
eCommerce Guidelines
HOME | TEXT ONLY | DISABILITY SERVICES | HELP CENTRAL | CONSUMER INFORMATION | CONTACT US
©
Curators of the University of Missouri. DMCA and other copyright information. University of Missouri-Kansas City | Kansas City, MO 64110 | (816) 235-1000
UMKC is an equal opportunity/access/affirmative action/pro-disability and veteran employer and does not discriminate on the basis of sex in our education programs or activities, pursuant to Title IX and 34 CFR Part 106. For more information, visit our UMKC Statement of Nondiscrimination. Issues with this website?.
